https://artists.ca/privacy_policy

HomeAboutMembership / ChaptersFederation GalleryMember DirectoryEducation HomepageGet InvolvedMember ResourcesShow Submissions
Home> Privacy Policy
Print
Privacy Policy
Our Commitment to your Privacy
The Federation of Canadian Artists respects your right to personal privacy. We will not rent or sell your personal information to anyone outside of the FCA. By providing your information, or becoming a member, you agree to receive ongoing updates from the FCA about industry topics, upcoming events and other relevant announcements via email, direct mail and telephone. You can unsubscribe or change your contact preferences at any time by emailing us at fcaoffice@artists.ca.
Why do we collect your personal information?
We respect your right to personal privacy. We will not rent or sell your personal information to anyone outside the FCA. We collect your information for the following reasons:
Membership and Event or Course RegistrationWhen you become a FCA member or register for an event or course, you may need to provide us with contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so that we can process your registration.
Providing you with updatesThe FCA provides ongoing updates about industry topics, upcoming events, exclusive member benefits, surveys and other relevant announcements via email, direct mail, fax and telephone.  You can receive updates by joining the FCA or visiting our website at www.artists.ca  To enroll, we will collect your contact information (such as name, address, telephone number and e-mail address). This information will only be used to contact you about the FCA or our affiliates. You can unsubscribe or change your contact preferences at any time by emailing us at fcaoffice@artists.ca
Participation in a Juried Shows, Promotions, or SurveysFrom time to time, we run juried shows, promotions, and surveys. If you choose to participate, you may be asked for contact information as well as additional optional survey information.   We may also summarize and analyze survey information in a way that no longer identifies the respondents.
Other Information we collectWe may use non-personal information to compile tracking reports regarding Web Site user demographics, Web Site traffic patterns, and Web Site purchases, and then provide those reports to advertisers and others. None of the tracking information in the reports can be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users. We may also link tracking information with personal information voluntarily provided by Web Site users. Once such a link is made, all of the linked information is treated as personal information and will be used and disclosed only in accordance with this Policy.
Who Has Access to my Personal Information?
Disclosure to FCA Board Members, Staff and select VolunteersThe FCA will only provide access to your personal information to those board members, Staff and select Volunteers who need it in order to assist you or to analyze our performance in order to measure and improve the FCA. Board Members, Staff and select Volunteers are kept up-to-date with regards to our privacy and security practices and are required to sign confidentiality agreements upon joining the board.
Disclosure to Service ProvidersWe may use leading service providers to assist us with key business functions. We will only share information necessary for these service providers to perform their role in serving you on behalf of the FCA. To reduce the risk of fraud or misuse of personal information, these third parties will be required to sign a confidentiality agreement that binds them to keep all member/customer information confidential.
Legal DisclosureThe FCA may disclose your information as permitted or required by law; for example: to a government institution or other person or entity that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information; where we have reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity; to comply with a subpoena or warrant or an order made by a court, person or entity with jurisdiction to compel the production of information; to comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information; to our legal counsel; and to an archival institution.
How does the FCA Protect my Information?
The security of your personal information is a high priority for the FCA. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse. Membership information s processed and stored in secure, dedicated confidential databases in Vancouver, BC, Canada. Although we cannot take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data by a third party, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.
When is my Information Removed?
We keep your information only as long as we need it for the products and services you're using and for a reasonable time thereafter or to meet any legal requirements. We destroy your information when it is no longer needed, or we remove your personally identifiable information.
How do I Access my Personal Information?
At any time, you can check your information to verify, update, or correct it, and have any obsolete information removed.  You can also review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it; ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information; or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.
If you would like to access, change or remove your personal information; or if you have any questions, concerns or complaints about the privacy policies stated here, please contact us at:
Patrick MeyerExecutive DirectorFederation of Canadian Artists1241 Cartwright St. Granville IslandVancouver, BC  V6H 4B7Telephone: 604-681-2744Email:fcaoffice@artists.ca
We will respond to your request or investigate your concern as quickly as we can. For your protection, the FCA  may require identification for verification.
Federation of Canadian Artists HomeAboutMembership / ChaptersFederation GalleryMember DirectoryEducation HomepageGet InvolvedMember ResourcesShow SubmissionsContact UsPrivacy Policy Login
